Ali Rahimi



Esfahan/Iran +989135732644 alirahimii@protonmail.com

github in linkedin

SUMMARY

I'm a Software Engineer. Assign me with some tasks, I'll find the solutions and get it done. Experienced in development of complex Android Applications with the new stacks such as Kotlin, JetPackComponents (MVVM/ROOM/DATABINDING/etc), Dependency Injection(Dagger), Dataflow(Retrofit/Moshi/Coroutines) and etc.

EDUCATION

Isfahan Univercity of Technology

2013-2019

B.Sc. in Software Engineering

• Course Work: Advanced Mathematics and Physics, Software Engineering Principals(Design, Architecture, OOP, etc) Data Structure, OS Architecture, Theory of Formal Languages(Compilers, Automata), Databases, Computer Networks, Software Engineering, IT Engineering, Statistics, AI, Computer Graphics, Economics, Microprocessors and etc.

EXPERIENCE _

Full front-end Android Developer

Sep 2014 - March 2015

PulseCo, Freelancer, IR

Pantomime Game/Application with cool UX and UI written in Java for android 2.1 to 4.0. The APK still works perfectly in android 10!

iOS Developer

May 2015 - August 2015

PulseCo, Freelancer, IR

I learned native iOS development with Swift by developing an existing android application to iOS. I really liked and appreciated the Apple Architecture Design guidelines (MVC)

Full front-end Android Developer

Nov 2015 - July 2016

TreeCo, Freelancer, IR

Android Online and Offline Game/Application written in Java. Key features: Notifications, Restfull and Web Sockets Communication With Server, Registration/Friend Management/Chat, Encrypted Coin System, Analytics and etc.

Front-end Android Developer

Oct 2016 - Dec 2016

Remote Freelancer, Malaysia

• Smart Pledge System designed and implemented for funding a political party in malaysia. I implemented some basic data flow, authentication, subscribing to a payment plan and actual paying functionality with PayPall or Cards.

FullStack Developer

March 2019 - August 2019

Bachelor Project

Persian Sign Language Learning Assistant Native Android Application for children with the use of Visual Learning techniques by providing videos and images. New learning modules could be added to the existing app from a node js server.

Full front-end Android and Android TV Developer

August 2019 - October 2020

Remote Freelancer, EU

Stack: Kotlin,MVVM,Databiding,RoomDB,WorkManager,Retrofit,Dependency Injection(Dagger) and Kotlin Coroutines. Worked and communicated in English with a European company.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES
SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT
Programming Paradigms | GIT | CLI | Agile Methodology | DevOps Lifecycles

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES
Jupyter | Matplotplib | Numpy | Pandas | Scikit-learn | Gym | PyTorch | Tensorflow
RXSwift | PromiseKit | CocoaPods | Autolayout/DSLs

LANGUAGES
Native: Turkish Fluent: English Beginner: German